Excuse me, sir. Sir, is this your house?
Can I help you?
Is this your house?
Who are you?
What did you do to
be able to afford this place?
In 2003, I started a tech company, and
I sold my last company for $235 million.
$235 billion?
That's right.
Sir, sir, is this your Ferrari?
Yes.
What did you do to
be able to afford a Ferrari?
I sold the biggest company in my industry in 2018.
What type of company?
It was this f***ing company.
How much did you sell your company for?
Almost $100 billion.
$100 billion?
Yes.
Last year, we did not do a billion.
No?
No, we did $850 million for the year.
You did $850 million?
Absolutely.
We're going to do a billion this year.
How can somebody become a multimillionaire in today's world?
Oh, my God.
Everyone thinks Miami is where the money is.
The flashy cars, the
wild parties, the influencers everywhere.
But if you really want to see where
the old money is, the quiet wealth, the billionaires,
well, you got to head about an hour
north up to Boca Raton in Palm Beach,
which is where we're at right now, guys.
We're literally on billionaire's row out here.
And I'm going to be going up
door to door, door knocking, ringing the bells
to be able to figure out if we can talk
to these people to figure out how they made their money
and built their fortune.
Guys, I'm going to be
cold approaching multimillionaires and billionaires today
to get their advice for you.
So stay tuned from start to finish
because this video is going to be insane.
With that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
Go.
Excuse me, sir.
Is this your house?
I started a business media channel
that I grew to 14 million followers.
Thank you, sir.
You guys, this is the difficult thing about this
video because we are in one of the richest
neighborhoods, probably one of the
richest areas in the entire country.
It is very hard to get access
to these people to do interviews with them.
But all we can do is keep on going.
I always say that volume negates luck and
every no is a step closer to a yes.
You guys, come on.
Hi, ma'am.
My name is James.
And I started a...
A business social media channel called The School
of Hard Knocks that I grew to 14 million
followers.
I go all over the world.
We're not interested.
Okay.
Have a nice day.
Hi.
How you doing, man?
Good.
How are you?
Question for you.
Yeah.
So I grew a social media channel to
about 14 million followers going all over the world
asking homeowners what they did to
be able to afford their houses.
Is this your spot right here?
Yeah.
Not interested.
Oh, man.
Have a good one, brother.
Have a good one.
Here we go.
I'm feeling this one.
Please wait while you're...
The call is connected.
Hello?
Yeah.
Hey, question for you.
So my name is James.
I started a business social media channel called
The School of Hard Knocks that I grew
to 14 million followers.
I travel all over the world interviewing business owners.
I've interviewed Tom Cruise, Shaquille O'Neal, Mark
Cuban, and I'm doing a series where I'm
going to nice neighborhoods to ask beautiful
homeowners like two or three questions on
their advice to the younger generation.
I'm just not interested, but thanks for the opportunity.
Absolutely.
Have a great day, sir.
Thank you.
All right, you guys.
This is probably like a $20 million house.
Out here in South Florida.
We're going to go up, see if the homeowners are
here and what they did to be able to afford
this place.
Come on.
How you doing, sir?
So I started the biggest business media channel in
the world where I go all over the world
asking beautiful homeowners their best
advice to the younger generation.
Could I get 30?
What's that?
What do you want?
Just advice to the younger generation on how
you were able to afford such a beautiful home.
I go all over the world.
Yeah.
Thanks, everybody.
No problem.
Well, so we've interviewed...
You can't get everybody, man.
You can't get everybody.
Hey, we tried, man.
You heard the pitch.
I thought it was effective, but
it's tough out here, you guys.
Question for you.
So I started a social media
channel at the University of Texas.
I grew it to about 14 million followers
where I go all over the world just interviewing
business owners and people for
advice to the younger generation.
I thought you had a beautiful house.
Did you buy this house?
Is this your house?
My husband did.
He did?
Is he here?
No.
What did he do?
He's on the way to Italy.
He's in private equity.
He's in private equity?
I say work hard.
Work hard?
Follow your dreams.
Okay.
I love it.
Don't listen to what other people say.
Any advice to somebody trying
to find the right life partner?
Values.
You have to have things in common.
What do you have to
be aligned on, like most importantly?
Your interest and like values.
Okay.
I think values are very important.
Well, thank you.
Because if you don't have values and morals, right?
Yeah, 100%.
I hate to say it because what else to do?
Hey, she said it.
She said it, not me.
Arch, guys, we are at our next
sector of mansions out here in Boca Raton.
I mean, look at these places right here.
The house right over here, they just
pulled up in a G-Wagon in the drive.
We're going to see if we can go
up and get some game for you guys.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir.
Is this your house?
Who are you?
I grew a channel to 14 million followers.
I started the biggest business media channel
in the entire world, getting advice for young
entrepreneurs.
What did you do to
be able to afford this place?
Yeah, I was in the electronic cigarette business.
E-cigarettes?
Yeah, e-cigarettes.
How long were you in the business?
I built the world's largest brand
in under five years with 10 grand.
So you started with 10 grand?
10 grand.
What's the most you made in a single year?
Give me the biggest year you had.
100 million.
100 million?
And could I interview you for
one minute real quick for the channel?
I'll give you two.
Is that okay?
Yeah.
How did you scale from a
10 to 100 million dollar company?
What was your secret to scaling?
My secret was going store to store,
mouth to mouth with my electronic cigarettes.
I'd spend 20 hours on a line
at 7-Eleven saying, hey, you smoke Marlboro?
Try my brand.
Cancer free.
You can do it anywhere.
And by the way, your wife's going to love
the way you smell and your kids are going
to be happy.
You're not going to kill yourself from deadly cigarettes.
So it's like real guerrilla marketing.
So store by store, mouth by mouth.
My son says, dad, tell the story.
So every week I log 140 hours.
I'd have all those customers that went to
go buy a cup of coffee, bought my Logic.
The store made 40% gross profit.
I got paid up front.
I always say no
consignment, commitment, guaranteed the product.
And store by store, I built my brand.
Did you have anybody that doubted you?
Everybody.
I was a personal trainer.
I had 39 failed companies.
You said you had 39 companies
that failed, but that 40th one hit.
It was a rocket ship.
What was it about that 40th company
that just enabled it to take off?
It was at the moment that somebody blew smoke
in front of me at a meeting and I thought
it was real smoke.
But then they said it's
electronic cigarette, cancer free smoking.
I said, this is what God just
put me on the earth to do.
Get millions of people off deadly cigarettes.
And I went all in.
And it was like out of a.
Motion picture.
We had 100,000 points of distribution.
We broke 100 million in 18 months.
We were the hottest brand in the nation.
And we basically, in less than five years,
we sold the company to Japan Tobacco through
Goldman Sachs.
It still feels like a movie.
Were you ever afraid of competition?
You know what?
Competition fuels me.
Messi wouldn't be as good without Ronaldo.
They fuel each other.
The yin and yang.
So you see a competitive market.
You're not afraid to go in there.
No, I love to beat competition.
What do you do differently from
everybody else when you identify a market?
Okay, so this is what I did.
This is a crazy story.
I identified in the electronic cigarette market.
One is rechargeables were defective.
Had a lot of returns.
They were very expensive.
How did you find that problem to identify?
So I went in the stores, asked
questions, and said, what are your best-selling brands?
And what are the challenges you have?
How important was it for you asking the
right questions to the people that find the problems?
No, the right questions are everything.
I mean, look at Tim Ferriss.
Tim Ferriss talks about asking
the right questions are everything.
Going in, giving the highest profit margin,
giving them a product that we guaranteed always
worked.
We knew we had to deliver
the best product with the best experience.
So we went all in with disposable.
We were really the only ones selling disposable for $9.99.
Store paid $5.95.
They made 40% GP.
But how do you give them the right experience?
There are four levels of nicotine.
There was like 2.7, 1.8, 1.5.
Then we had a low below 1.
So what I did as a scrappy
guerrilla marketer is I had these white boxes.
And I wrote on them Marlboro, Newport, Marlboro Light.
What did that do?
It identified that smoker and
which logic they should choose.
Because there were 30, 40 different brands on the counter.
We had a plain white box.
I just wrote the brand of the cigarettes on them.
This was so different because simplicity sells.
Yeah.
So right away.
Oh, you want Marlboro?
Take Logic Platinum.
Oh, you do Marlboro Light?
Logic Gold Label.
This was great.
I'll tell you another thing I did.
I dropped the secrets in some high ticket
call masterminds that people hire me to speak in.
So I'll drop some bombs here.
Trademarks.
Trademarks are very powerful.
You can make claims with trademarks.
What is one of the greatest trademarks
of all time that I did for Logic?
They said to me, Howie, if you want
to claim that you're the most trusted brand,
you need to get a focus group.
Focus group?
I don't have $250 for a focus group.
I started with $10,000.
How can you get out of the focus group?
And just claim something.
It's like the five hour energy guy.
He never claimed it was five hours of energy.
He just called that.
That was the brand.
That was his brand, right?
People try to sue him.
And he said, No, that's my brand.
All I say is feel in minutes last for hours.
So I took that concept for myself and
I said, Okay, I'm going to register under electronic
cigarettes, the most trusted brand.
And it went through.
2,000 taxis in New York.
Logic, the most trusted brand.
I was the first one on taxis in New York.
I had 2,000 taxis.
$150 a month.
Advertising.
I was in every bodega.
I took over New York.
And the five boroughs.
I didn't even go to the West Coast.
I stayed focused on the East Coast.
So you mastered guerrilla marketing.
I mastered guerrilla marketing by being in
the streets, in the stores, talking to the
managers, talking to the workers.
And I still do it today.
You do better than anybody else.
I do it the best of my ability.
I don't compare to anybody else.
I just look at my results
and my results speak for themselves.
You got amazing advice, my friend.
All right, cool.
Thank you so much for your time.
I appreciate you.
You guys, we just walked up to and
interviewed a $100 million entrepreneur at his compound,
you guys.
This is one of the
craziest houses that I've ever seen.
In my entire life.
And he made his fortune doing what?
Inventing an e-cigarettes company.
He disrupted an entire market.
And he did it by solving problems.
He said that I got tired
of seeing people die from cigarette smoke.
So he wanted to convert them over to e-cigarettes.
There you go.
You can make money any
way you want if you're entrepreneurial.
This video just got off to a crazy start.
But we got to go get this next
one out here in Boca Raton, you guys.
Come on.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Ma'am, is this your house?
What did you do to
be able to afford this place?
I'm a tech entrepreneur.
So I go all over the world
interviewing the most successful people to help them.
The younger generation.
I'm going all over asking homeowners what they
did to be able to afford multi-million dollar houses.
I wanted to know if I could
interview you for one minute real quick.
Just a minute.
It'll be worth it.
It's for the younger generation.
Is that okay?
Yeah, sure.
So what business made you the most amount of money?
In 2003, I started a tech company.
And I sold my last company for $235 million.
$235 billion?
That's right.
That's a lot of ebbs.
Hey, hey.
That's a lot.
That's why we live here.
How did you get the money to start that business?
Oh my gosh.
My grandma gave me a $10,000 loan.
You got a loan from your grandma?
Grandma.
She didn't even know what the internet was.
How did you convince her to give you a loan?
You know what?
After nobody else would give me money, I knew she was
the one person that would always make a bet on me.
And I told her the
internet was going to be huge.
What did you see that early that inspired you to
kind of go create a tech company in internet marketing?
Because when I think 20 years ago,
that's in like the very early 2000s.
That was when people were questioning whether that was going
to be like a boom or bust sort of thing.
What did you see that made you want
to stand out and go build a company there?
Well, I'd already worked for
a company that did go bust.
And they raised $100 million.
And I thought, hey, I think
I can do this better myself.
Wow.
So you got the $10,000 loan.
Did you raise any more
money at any point in time?
No, I didn't.
I used the $10,000 and I
bootstrapped it for my kitchen table.
So what were you doing?
Like who were you selling to?
What were your customers?
Selling to advertisers.
I was trying to displace
the billboards and the yellow pages.
I mean, this was really early on.
What was that thing that you did to be
able to set up the exit for over $200 million?
Honestly, it's innovation, market demand, timing.
Luck plays a lot to do with it.
And the people.
I had great people.
No one's successful alone, especially in tech.
I don't know how to code.
But I definitely know how to find the
number one person as a CTO that does.
Were you a good saleswoman?
Oh, yeah.
The best.
You sell well?
Oh, yes.
Of course.
Give me a little 30-second
long sales masterclass right here.
Somebody, they're struggling to close deals.
They're struggling to bring that
revenue into their business right now.
What's your best sales advice for anybody in business?
My best negotiation advice is not
to let emotion come into a deal.
So whether it's something good or something bad, the
moment it gets emotional or you get emotional, you lose.
How do you control that, though?
Because when tempers are flaring, when you're feeling this.
You're feeling this in a certain way inside.
How did you control that when you're in that room?
It takes time.
It's a skill.
It's a skill that you have to really focus on.
I think the best and most successful
people I know, don't let emotion control them.
And they'll wait it out.
Now, talk to me about how
you were able to scale the company.
Because a lot of entrepreneurs, they'll be
lucky to get to a million in revenue.
It's like 0.1% get to 10 million.
And then let alone you
went from 10 to 100 million.
What was your secret to scaling this company?
Oh, my gosh.
Having great mentors.
And the easiest way to find a mentor, I
could be your mentor, is saying these three words.
Let's have coffee.
Honestly, symbol as coffee makes a huge difference.
Because it's 15 minutes.
And if you can get the mentor,
your ability to multiply your success is significant.
So finding the right mentors, I cannot tell you.
If you don't have a mentor,
you will not be successful either.
Do you have a mentor?
I do.
Oh, good.
See, that's why you're you.
I have a couple.
Okay.
It makes a huge.
I, today, have so many mentors,
depending on what business I'm running.
I'm running a lot of them.
I have a mentor in every
single one that's already been successful.
The mentor doesn't have to be someone 20 years ahead.
It can be someone one year.
Just someone that has already been where you
want to go, has done what you want to
do, and actually cares about you and your growth.
So after exiting your tech
companies, you're still building companies.
Yes.
Oh my gosh.
I got four right now.
You have four companies right now.
Yes.
Are they diversified?
Diversified.
I got two tech company.
I got a web three company, a predictive
intelligence company, a beauty company, and a beverage
company.
What's keeping you going?
Because you're set for life.
Like, you know, your kids' kids
aren't going to have to work.
Like, what is really keeping you going
to be able to keep on building companies?
Is it just the love of the game or what?
I love the love of the game.
I love to win and I love to
help people and I love to help entrepreneurs.
I've invested in over 150 companies because my grandma
made a bet on me and I want to
pay that forward.
And what's your name?
Kim.
It's great to meet you.
Hi.
Guys, these Florida moguls are going crazy right
now and I'm headed to go get my next
one.
But I want to give you one of the best
pieces of advice that I've ever received from a billionaire,
which is that your ability to communicate will
determine how far you go in the business
world.
But here's the problem.
Writing clear and confident messages
to heavy hitters isn't always easy.
Especially when it comes to professional
emails, proposals, or even Slack messages.
But that's where Grammarly comes in.
Grammarly is an AI writing partner that works
inside of your favorite apps like Gmail, Notion,
and even Slack, helping you write better
and faster without having to switch tools constantly.
You can literally go from a rough draft
to a polished message within minutes, not hours.
You can rewrite, rephrase, and adjust the tone
of your message all with just one click.
And it even tailors your writing based on
the audience you're trying to reach and the
goals of your message.
So what you say, you do.
And that's where the best part is.
It's free to use.
And all you have to do is go down
and click the link in the description of this video,
or go to grammarly.com slash hardknock05 and
you can use Grammarly today for free.
With that being said, let's get back to the video.
Sir, sir, is this your Ferrari?
Yes.
What did you do to
be able to afford a Ferrari?
I sold the biggest company in my industry in 2018.
What type of company?
It was a specialty finance company.
How much did you sell your company for?
Almost $100 billion.
$100 billion?
Yes.
Could I interview you for one minute real quick?
Sure, I've got a few minutes.
How long have you been a business owner?
So I've been an owner since
2000, so about 25 years now.
Over these 25 years, what's the
greatest lesson that you've learned about entrepreneurship
that you give to somebody about to
start their first company in today's world?
So I've worked for three of the biggest companies
in the world, and I was in a senior management
position in those companies.
And what I learned is it's a lot better
to make money for yourself and the people that
work for you as opposed to really big companies.
So the best advice I can give is to
start something on your own if you really want to
make it big.
Bet on yourself.
Did you come from a lot of money?
I did not.
Blue Collar neighborhood, Williamsburg, Brooklyn.
Dad was a mason.
Mom was a housewife.
So what was your turning point to financial freedom?
I worked at a big company
and had a really good mentor.
He taught me a lot.
And he was the one who said, if you really
want to be successful and make a lot of money,
it's not going to happen if
you're working for a big company.
You have to find different alternative ways to make money.
So I started a little side business while
I was working full time and realized that
that was my passion.
Again, the message is betting on yourself.
And what was the biggest risk that you took?
The biggest risk that you took throughout your career?
Biggest risk I took is probably one that I
took in my early 60s, which is where I am
right now.
And that's raising a lot of money from
people that trust me, millions of dollars and being
responsible for that.
It was easy to do that when I was
younger, but once things started to set in, the enormous
responsibility to manage other people's
money is something that's really important.
So in your 60s, you're still taking risks?
I'm still taking risks and I'm not stopping.
As a matter of fact, we're starting a restaurant
in about two weeks and some people see one
restaurant.
I'm starting a chain of restaurants.
Whenever I do something, I try
not to focus on the present.
I try to focus on the future and have a
vision about what it's going to become in the future.
And you're in the top part of the top 1%.
What are you investing in right now in today's world?
So they used to say it's 100 minus your age.
I have a broker's license.
I was on Wall Street and 100 minus my
age would mean I should only be 35% in equities.
I'm 95% in equities.
You're 95% in equities?
Yes.
In the stock market?
In the stock market, but I've also invested
in a cryptocurrency fund and I put a pretty
significant amount of business in there,
whereas Bitcoin is 40% of the holding.
So I like crypto.
I'm starting to really understand it and
started to see that it's the next gen.
Do you think people should buy some cryptocurrency?
I do, but I think it should
only be a percentage of their portfolio.
So if someone has a modest risk profile, it
should probably be 10 to 15% of their profile.
It's 25% of my profile.
What was the best financial
decision you made throughout your career?
Becoming an entrepreneur.
No question.
Would you have done it any other way?
I would not have done it any other way.
I wouldn't change anything.
I'm happy sitting in a Ferrari right
now and I'm happy where it ended up.
All right, you guys, so I have
a special surprise for you all right now.
Since we're in Boca Raton, it was only right that
I hit up a good mentor of mine, my billionaire
friend, Sean Mike, who built several
nine figure and billion dollar companies.
His company right now that he's running has
done $5 billion in sales and he invited this
out to interview him at his house for you
guys to give you guys the blueprint on how
to become multimillionaires in today's world.
But let's go meet with him right now.
There he is.
What's up, man?
How's it going, my friend?
How are you, bro?
Good, man.
I'm excited to be here.
Good to see you.
I have no doubt about it, dude.
Remind the people right now, how much
money did you make this last year?
We did $850 million for the year.
$850 million?
Yes, sir.
That's a lot of M's.
It's a lot.
It's a lot of work.
Made a major difference in the world.
A lot of people made a lot
of money at the company, which is amazing.
What are you going to do this year?
We'll do a billion.
It'll be the first time I've
done a billion in a year.
That's incredible.
It is an incredible number.
I come all the way out here to ask
you how you got rich and how the younger generation
watching can become wealthy in today's world.
Can we make that happen?
Absolutely.
Anything for you, man.
What's the most amount of money?
Life insurance.
That's an unsexy business, though.
It's a very profitable business.
Yeah.
How is it profitable?
Because I find need-based products, right?
So real estate was my first business.
That was very good to me.
I did very well.
Then I got into waste management, and then
I had somebody introduce me to life insurance
business.
So when I can't run out of leads and
it's need-based and I can't run out of people to
get in front of, and all I got to
do is compete with everybody else that's out there, it's
an amazing business.
Did you come from a rich family?
Hell no.
My mother worked three jobs.
Me and my mother, my brother, and all the
cats and dogs she had and birds she could
get.
We lived in a little one-bedroom place.
I watched my mom struggle, and
my grandparents didn't have any money.
My father was from Iowa.
My mom raised us.
So no, man, we didn't have anything.
So what was your turning point to financial freedom?
Well, if you've watched your mother struggle,
as a boy, I got a little brother.
I watch my mom, and I see the stress on
her, and I see how it almost breaks her, and I
see how hard she worked.
And I played baseball, basketball, football.
My mom didn't go to my games,
not because my mom didn't love me.
My mom was working all
the time, morning, day, night, weekends.
I was like, I want my
mom to have a better opportunity.
Eventually.
I don't know who else is
going to provide it for her.
And I didn't want people to look at me
and our family, and I didn't want them to look
down on us.
Not because I thought I was better than them,
but I was just as good as they were.
And so I just wanted to
compete when I was a young age.
So I watched the way people looked at us because
of what we didn't have, and I was like, I'm
not going to live the
rest of my life that way.
I promise you that.
In my last interview, you gave me a
piece of advice that Arthur Blank gave you when
you asked him.
I'm going to challenge you again.
Give me the best piece of advice
that you've ever received from a mentor.
Think about the billionaires that you've met.
Give me a tactical piece of business advice
that you've learned in the last few years
of your life that have enabled you to
drastically scale and become a better entrepreneur and
just self-improve in general.
I was sitting in a meeting with a group
of people and we were looking at each other's
businesses.
And there was a gentleman that walked
in and he's a great guy, very successful.
He's like, I want to be
the most successful person nobody knows about.
Like I just keep it moving.
Billionaire many times over.
And he looked at me and he said,
you know the problem you have in your business?
And I said, I probably have multiple problems.
I'm trying to scale it.
He said, you're not delegating enough.
And I said, okay, what would you delegate?
He said, almost all of it.
You need to continue to do what you're doing,
but you need to build other people up by learning
how to delegate.
The art of delegation.
So he said, anything that you can teach somebody
to do, even if they're half as effective as
you at it, then you build something massive.
And maybe if you get out of the way and
delegate it and watch them grow, you'd be shocked what
you can accomplish.
That's how I'm on my way to a billion.
Like we'll do a billion this year.
How?
Because I've been able to delegate and have
all these amazing people that are like, I
can handle the lead gen part.
I'm over here doing the marketing.
Oh, recruiting.
I got that.
Oh, on the tech side?
Yeah, Sean, we're doing these five things over here.
And they have the ability and they know I'm comfortable.
Them going and making these decisions.
And guess what?
They're going to make bad decisions on occasion.
It's okay.
Give them the leeway to know that they're
going to fall on their face on occasion as
well.
So that's been actually probably the best
piece of advice I've gotten over the last
number of years now to continue to scale my business.
You can only go so far when you're trying
to do too many jobs, fit too many roles.
Because there's people that are
distant and they leave the business.
And I think that's a problem.
I've exited businesses.
I did a real estate, waste management, life insurance.
The ones that have been successful, I stayed around.
When I sold my real estate
company, they should have kept me around.
They should have.
They didn't.
They were like, okay.
And a couple of years later,
the whole thing just fell apart.
Waste management company sold to a
massive national company that had the infrastructure,
but some of the guys transferred over and still stayed.
Life insurance, I stayed involved because I love
the business I'm in and I want to continue
to take it to the next level.
You're never the only person that can do it.
Are you a good salesman?
I'm the best salesman you'll meet.
Unlike the other guys that tell you
the best salesman, I am the best salesman.
Give me a 30 second sales masterclass right here.
At the end of the day, you have to have
such great confidence and you have to be so presumptive.
No matter what you're doing, you can't ask for anything.
You instruct somebody.
If I have a nice job,
I'm going to be a good salesman.
If I have a need-based product and you're
my lead-based client, you have to be in the
lead selling bit.
I'm not going to cold call or cold knock.
You'll fail.
So you have to get leads.
You have to be presumptive.
When you say presumptive, you mean assume the sale?
Yeah.
Like I'm at the airport yesterday and
the guy says to me, ah, he's stumbling.
So then he restates his thought and says, would
you like to tip on the card or do you
want to give me cash?
That's presumptive.
I'm like, do that.
Don't go, well, we have a tip cup.
No, would you like to tip on the card, sir?
Or do you want to tip with cash?
And if I have a product that you've already
said you need, all I have to do is
cut through all the garbage and go, James, you understand.
Tell people the truth.
They're dying for the truth.
What are clients afraid of?
What are buyers afraid of?
Being lied to.
Their number one fear is being lied to.
Not paying too much.
They don't want you to lie to them.
So I'll give you one statement to change your life.
No matter who you're selling anything to, you
say, hey, James, may I ask you a question?
Yeah.
Do I have your permission to be
ridiculously, pathetically, brutally honest with you this
entire time we're talking about the product?
No matter what it is, you're totally fine
with me telling you the truth no matter what?
Yes.
I go, I don't mind life insurance.
And I go, James, it's going to cost
you this much because you're older and your health.
James, your house, your roof's leaking.
James, what's it going to cost?
A lot, James.
The entire thing's leaking.
You've given me permission to be honest with you.
And also, sales is just,
it's a marathon, not a sprint.
People are not looking to be enamored or tricked.
They want the truth.
And if you're confident, I'm confident.
If you're uncomfortable, I immediately think
you're lying to me because you're uncomfortable.
And my favorite line in sales
is, here's what we're going to do.
Because it becomes a joke.
Here's what we're going to do.
James, I hear you on all that.
No, I understand what you're saying.
Today's not a great day to do it.
Here's what we're going to do.
So it's safe to say that
you could sell water to a fish?
Yeah.
And it's funny because when people tell me,
they're like, I could sell snow cones to Eskimos
and ketchup to white gloves.
I'm like, dude, sales doesn't require talent.
The reason I'm good at it is I'm very teachable.
I look people in the eye and I'll tell
them no matter what they need to hear, I'm going
to tell them the truth.
I'm going to stand behind it.
I'm going to work my ass off.
I'm going to invest in leads and I'm
going to invest in me and getting better.
So other people could beat me if they'd
outwork me because it doesn't require any talent.
See the biggest misnomer about sales, anybody
that tells you they're a good salesperson
because they're just good sales, they're lying.
They just work hard and have more leads.
Am I good at it?
Yes, I've done it a lot.
I've had plenty of reps.
There's also guys in the UFC that
have been fighting since they were six.
They're good at it.
Why?
They've been fighting everybody their entire lives.
They're starving and they've been fighting everybody.
They know where to put their hands.
They train every day, eight, 10, 12 hours a day.
I'm going to be real.
That's some of the best sales advice I've ever heard.
Thank you, man.
I told you.
You told me.
I was like, I'm a salesman.
I was like, the other people aren't.
So I had to step up.
That was some day right there.
Guys, $850 million in a single year.
He said, I'm doing a billion dollars this year.
That entire interview was a straight masterclass.
I can't believe we just linked
up with the legend, Sean Mike.
Once again, you know he was going to bring
a million dollars worth of game for you guys.
Not a million, a billion dollars worth of game.
But let's keep this video rolling
and go get another one, you guys.
Come on.
This is one of the craziest
houses I've seen in my entire life.
I can't even call this a house.
This is a compound.
Let's see if we can get some free game.
How you doing, sir?
I'm good.
Thanks.
How are you?
Good.
Is this your house?
Yes.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What did you do to
be able to afford this place?
I have a personal question.
Yeah.
So I grew a channel to 14 million followers.
I go all over the world interviewing business
owners and the most successful people to help
the younger generation.
I wanted to know if I could interview you
for one minute real quick, if that was cool.
Okay.
Come on in.
Is that okay?
Could we do it out here for lighting purposes?
You know what?
Let's do it outside, in the back.
Is that okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you, sir.
What line of business were you in?
I'm in real estate.
I did it in my first one.
I bought it in my first fourplex.
It was an accident.
It was like truly, it was like
a one conversation in a family members.
They said they owned one and
they lived in the other three.
And that's what I did.
I bought it my first fourplex.
Actually.
Yeah.
I live in one and I rent the other three.
That's how it started.
People say you have to have a ton
of money to get started in real estate.
Do you agree with that?
Hell no.
You don't need shit.
When I bought my first fourplex, I bought it,
I spent $50,000 that I borrow and I rent
and sell all my cars.
The second fourplex, I bought with 5,000.
The third one, I bought with 3,000.
The last deal, I think I bought $72 million.
I bought with zero money.
What do you mean zero money?
Zero money.
Did you borrow money or what?
Nope.
It's a creative financing brother.
Creative financing.
Yeah.
There's no banks, man.
How does that work?
Well, you got to have, you got to build
your reputation and you got to build the credit.
And there's a people that want to give you
the money all the time and you just got to
find the deals.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
I can tell you there was
a year that I lost $250 million.
You lost $250 million?
Yeah.
And I remember, I don't, I
don't learn shit from my successes.
Like I can tell you how many millions I made.
It's not about that.
It's about the lessons and the
failure I made in my life.
How did you lose $250 million in a year?
Well, the market dropped and so it was like
a lot of equity and a lot of cash.
So what did you learn from that?
Like not put all your eggs in
one basket or what was that lesson?
No, no.
This is exactly that I, you know, I play safe.
You know, when you get bigger, you
get more comfortable and comfortable and then you
overanalyze yourself and you forget about yourself
because you got all the answers within you.
What was the lowest point in your life?
It was four years ago when I almost committed suicide.
You almost, you almost committed suicide?
Yeah.
I almost died right there.
That boat.
I almost took that, took my scuba diving gear,
went to the ocean and did the last dive.
Why?
Well, because I was always looking
for validation from the outside world.
That's why I'm so successful in the businesses.
Because anything I thought it turns
to gold, but I forgot about me.
My businesses becomes my identity versus I'm, I
have my own identity to grow my businesses.
So you don't think money buys happiness?
Oh hell no.
Fuck no.
Fuck.
Oh dude, don't get me started.
Money doesn't buy you.
The only thing money buys you, it buys you time.
And then what you do with that, you
know, if you're a douche bag, you're going to
be a bigger douche bag.
If you're a good human being, the
money is going to give you more.
It just amplifies the person.
Amplifies exactly who you are.
So what is it that enabled you
to find that true fulfillment and happiness?
Like when you hit rock bottom mentally, when
you almost took your life, what was that actionable
step that you take?
There's a lot of people that are
at rock bottom right now, mentally, physically, spiritually.
What advice would you give to them?
Thank you for asking the question.
I appreciate that.
What advice would you give to them?
It doesn't matter how hard time you're
going through right now, it's going to pass.
And it doesn't matter like you're on the
top of the mountains, it's also going to pass.
So connect with yourself.
Fulfill yourself.
Work on yourself.
And you know what?
Baby steps.
You know, you don't have to win.
You don't have to immediately get enormous huge wins.
Just a little day at the time,
1% at the time, just little steps.
And the most important, talk to somebody.
Do not hide.
Like you know what we men do?
We freaking hide.
When we go through shit, we don't tell anybody.
And what you got to do, you got to
really sit down with somebody and you got to make
sure that you have a trust with people.
Not somebody at the bar.
That's not what I'm saying.
And really, drug, not alcohol, all
this shit doesn't take you anywhere.
We have all the addictions because
what happened is we're sedating with that.
And I was sedating with work.
And then I was sedating with working hours.
I was an Ironman, you know,
then one through a second winning them.
So it's like this is just sedation.
You know, workaholism, workaholism, alcoholism,
drugs, everything, gambling, food, all this
stuff.
It's a sedation because we don't want to
be in the present moment and, you know, connect
with ourselves.
If you die tomorrow and all that was
left was one guiding principle that you could give
to somebody to become the best
version of themselves, what would that be?
The only message I still, I'm not going to change.
Yeah.
But the only message I still want to
give to you is that you have everything, like
you got everything what you need already within you.
Go deep, search for it and work on yourself.
Be selfish for a while.
Do not get married too early and build this empire.
You are the biggest asset in
the world and you're the only one.
Take care of it.
Build a castle.
Everything else is abundance.
It will come.
You are love, you are abundant
and you got everything within you.
Go enjoy the journey, not the destination.
And the person you become on the
journey because we all want the shortcuts.
Take the detour because the person you're going
to become, it's going to help you in
life.
You got amazing advice, my friend.
Thank you so much for your time.
All right, you guys, that's a wrap on today's video.
He said, come on in.
I said, we want to do it out front.
He said, no, we got
to do it in the backyard.
And he just gave an amazing, wholesome interview, man.
Told us his full life
story, the highs and the lows.
But I need you guys to like and
subscribe for amazing content we've got coming every
single week.
Guys, I'm going all over the world to
interview the most successful and the wealthiest people
for you guys to learn from and implement
the information that they give you guys here on
this channel.
At the school of hard knocks.
And if you want to take it a step
further and be able to get access to the millionaires
and billionaires that I interview, well, you
can because every week, guys, I host live
calls with the people that I
interview, the eight, nine figure billionaire entrepreneurs
you see me interview.
I host live calls with them every
week inside of my private entrepreneur community.
If you want to join today, go down
and click the link in the description to join.
You can join right now for free.
This is a once in a lifetime opportunity
to get mentored from the biggest business owners
in the world to help you start building
the business of your dreams and create financial
freedom.
I can't wait to see you
on the inside of the community.
With that being said, I'll
see you in the next video.
I'll see you in the next video.